Yongsoo Song

Yongsoo.Song@microsoft.com
→ https://yongsoosong.github.io/
Building 99, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052
→ +1 (858) 249-9390

POSITIONS

Microsoft Research, Redmond, WA, United States

Senior Researcher, Cryptography Group

Jan 2019 – Present

University of California, San Diego, CA, United States

Postdoctoral Researcher, Department of Computer Science and Engineering

Jan 2018 – Dec 2018

EDUCATION

Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea

• M.S. and Ph.D. in Mathematical Sciences

Sep 2012 – Feb 2018

- Thesis: Homomorphic Encryption for Approximate Arithmetic
- Advisor: Prof. Jung Hee Cheon
- B.S. in Mathematical Sciences

Mar 2005 – Aug 2012

OVERVIEW

I am a Senior Researcher in the Cryptography and Privacy Research Group at MSR, interested in a broad range of topics in data security and privacy. My research focuses on cryptographic primitives for secure computation and their applications.

- Design and implementation of high-performance Homomorphic Encryption (HE) schemes
- Improving usability and flexibility of modern cryptographic technology
- Applications in machine learning

PUBLICATIONS

CONFERENCES

- [C11] H. Chen, W. Dai, M. Kim, and **Y. Song**, "Efficient Multi-Key Homomorphic Encryption with Packed Ciphertexts with Application to Oblivious Neural Network Inference," *The 26th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS 2019)*.
- [C10] H. Chen, I. Chillotti and **Y. Song**, "Multi-Key Homomorphic Encryption from TFHE," the 25th Annual International Conference on the Theory and Application of Cryptology and Information Security (ASIACRYPT 2019).
- [C09] H. Chen, I. Chillotti and Y. Song, "Improved Bootstrapping for Approximate Homomorphic Encryption," The 38th Annual International Conference on the Theory and Applications of Cryptographic Techniques (EUROCRYPT 2019).
- [C08] D. Kim and **Y. Song**, "Approximate Homomorphic Encryption over the Conjugate-invariant Ring," *The 21st Annual International Conference on Information Security and Cryptology (ICISC 2018*).
- [C07] X. Jiang, M. Kim, K. Lauter and Y. Song, "Secure Outsourced Matrix Computation and Application to Neural Networks," The 25th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS 2018).
- [C06] J. H. Cheon, K. Han, A. Kim, M. Kim and **Y. Song**, "A Full RNS Variant of Approximate Homomorphic Encryption," *The 25th Conference on Selected Areas in Cryptography (SAC 2018)*.
- [C05] J. H. Cheon, D. Kim, J. Lee, and Y. Song, "Lizard: Cut off the Tail! Practical Post-Quantum Public-Key Encryption from LWE and LWR," The 11th Conference on Security and Cryptography for Networks (SCN 2018).
- [C04] J. H. Cheon, K. Han, A. Kim, M. Kim, and **Y. Song**, "Bootstrapping for Approximate Homomorphic Encryption," *The 37th Annual International Conference on the Theory and Applications of Cryptographic Techniques (EUROCRYPT 2018)*.
- [C03] J. H. Cheon, A. Kim, M. Kim, and Y. Song, "Homomorphic Encryption for Arithmetic of Approximate Numbers," The 23rd International Conference on the Theory and Applications of Cryptology and Information Security (ASIACRYPT 2017).
- [C02] J. Kim, C. Lee, H. Shim, J. H. Cheon, A. Kim, M. Kim, and Y. Song, "Encrypting Controller using Fully Homomorphic Encryption for Security of Cyber-Physical Systems," The 6th IFAC Workshop on Distributed Estimation and Control in Networked Systems (NECSYS 2016).

[C01] J. H. Cheon, T. Kim, and **Y. Song**, "A Group Action on \mathbb{Z}_p^{\times} and the Generalized DLP with Auxiliary Inputs," *The 20th International Conference on Selected Areas in Cryptography (SAC 2013)*.

JOURNALS

- [J07] M. Kim, **Y. Song**, B. Li, and D. Micciancio, "Semi-parallel logistic regression for GWAS on encrypted data," *BMC Med. Genomics*, 2019.
- [J06] J. H. Cheon, D. Kim, Y. Kim and Y. Song, "Ensemble Method for Privacy-Preserving Logistic Regression based on Homomorphic Encryption," *IEEE Access* 10.1109/ACCESS.2018.2866697, 2018.
- [J05] A. Kim, **Y. Song**, M. Kim, K. Lee, J. H. Cheon, "Logistic Regression Model Training based on the Approximate Homomorphic Encryption," *BMC Med. Genomics*, 2018.
- [J04] Y. Jiang, J. Hamer, C. Wang, X. Jiang, M. Kim, Y. Song, Y. Xia, N. Mohammed, M. N. Sadat, and S. Wang, "SecureLR: Secure Logistic Regression Model via a Hybrid Cryptographic Protocol," *IEEE/ACM Transactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics*, 2018.
- [J03] J. H. Cheon, K. Han, S. Hong, H. J. Kim, J. Kim, S. Kim, H. Seo, H. Shim, and Y. Song, "Toward a Secure Drone System: Flying with Real-time Homomorphic Authenticated Encryption," *IEEE Access DOI 10.1109/ACCESS.2018.2819189*, 2018.
- [J02] M. Kim, **Y. Song**, S. Wang, Y. Xia, and X. Jiang, "Secure Logistic Regression Based on Homomorphic Encryption: Design and Evaluation," *JMIR Med Inform 2018;6*(2):*e19*, 2018.
- [J01] M. Kim, **Y. Song**, and J. H. Cheon, "Secure Searching of Biomarkers Using Hybrid Homomorphic Encryption Scheme," *BMC Med. Genomics.* 2017;10:42, 2017.

BOOK AND BOOK CHAPTERS

[B01] J. H. Cheon, T. Kim, and **Y. Song**, "The Discrete Logarithm Problem with Auxiliary Inputs," In *Algebraic Curves and Finite Fields. Cryptography and Other Applications*, Berlin, Boston: De Gruyter, 2014.

MANUSCRIPTS

- [E08] H. Chen, W. Dai, M. Kim and **Y. Song**, "Efficient Homomorphic Conversion Between (Ring) LWE Ciphertexts," 2019 (submitted to PKC 2020).
- [E07] H. Chen, M. Kim, I. Razenshteyn, D. Rotaru, Y. Song and S. Wagh, "Maliciously Secure Matrix Multiplication with Applications to Private Deep Learning," 2019 (submitted to EUROCRYPT 2020).
- [E06] H. Chen, L. Chua, K. Lauter and **Y. Song**, "On the concrete approximation factor of BKZ2.0 on uSVP lattices," 2019 (submitted to EUROCRYPT 2020).
- [E05] Y. Song, J. Cyranka, D. Kim and S. Gao, "Convergence and Oscillation of Low-Precision Stochastic Gradient Descent," 2019.
- [E04] J. H. Cheon, D. Kim, J. Lee, J. Shin, and **Y. Song**, "Instant Privacy-Preserving Biometric Authentication for Hamming Distance Matcher," 2018.
- [E03] D. Archer, L. Chen, J. H. Cheon, R. Gilad-Bachrach, R. A. Hallman, Z. Huang, X. Jiang, R. Kumaresan, B. A. Malin, H. Sofia, and Y. Song, "Applications of Homomorphic Encryption," *Draft Homomorphic Encryption Standard*, available at HomomorphicEncryption.org (white paper), 2017.
- [E02] J. H. Cheon and Y. Song, "Batch Fully Homomorphic Encryption over the Integers Revisited," 2016.
- [E01] J. H. Cheon and Y. Song, "Secure Sketch for Set Distance on Noisy Data," 2014.

PROJECTS / SOFTWARES

- [S04] "Microsoft SEAL: The Microsoft Simple Encrypted Arithmetic Library," https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/project/microsoft-seal/, 2019.
- [S03] "Full RNS Variant of HEAAN," https://github.com/HanKyoohyung/FullRNS-HEAAN, 2018.
- [S02] "Bootstrapping of HEAAN," https://github.com/kimandrik/HEAANBOOT, 2018.
- [S01] "Implementation of HEAAN," https://github.com/kimandrik/HEAAN, 2016.

PATENTS

[P08] J. H. Cheon, **Y. Song** and K. Han, "Method for Authenticating Evaluation Results of Homomorphic-Encrypted Data," KR20190005540A, 2019.

- [P07] J. H. Cheon and **Y. Song**, "Method for Authenticating Biometric Information Which Protects Biometric Information," KR101838008B1 and WO2018199713A1, 2017.
- [P06] H. Sim, J. H. Cheon, **Y. Song**, M. Kim, J. Kim, C. Lee, "Method for Processing Dynamic Data by Fully Homomorphic Encryption," KR101919940B1 and WO2018147497A1, 2017.
- [P05] J. H. Cheon, Y. Song and K. Han, "Terminal device for performing homomorphic encryption, server device for calculating encrypted messages, and methods thereof," KR101965628B1, 2016.
- [P04] J. H. Cheon and **Y. Song**, "Homomorphic Encryption Method of a Plurality of Messages Supporting Approximate Arithmetic of Complex Numbers," KR101861089B1, 2016.
- [P03] J. H. Cheon and Y. Song, "Homomorphic Encryption Method Supporting Floating-Point Arithmetic and Floating-Point Arithmetic Method for Encrypted Message Generated by the Same," KR101971215B1, 2019.
- [P02] J. H. Cheon and **Y. Song**, "Homomorphic Encryption Method by Which Ciphertext Size Is Reduced," KR101829267B1, 2018.
- [P01] J. H. Cheon, J.W. Kim, E. Kwon, K. Lee, H. Ryu and **Y. Song**, "Fingerprint Enrollment Method and Fingerprint Verification Method," KR20160133991A, 2016.

HONORS & AWARDS

• First Prize , iDASH Genomic Data Privacy and Security Protection Competition 20 http://www.humangenomeprivacy.org/2018/	Oct 2018
 First Prize, iDASH Genomic Data Privacy and Security Protection Competition 20 http://www.humangenomeprivacy.org/2017/ 	Oct 2017
 Excellence Award, Crypto Contest Korea Cryptography Forum. 	Oct 2017
 Second Prize, iDASH Genomic Data Privacy and Security Protection Competition 2 http://www.humangenomeprivacy.org/2016/ 	2016 Nov 2016
■ Best Award , Crypto Contest Korea Cryptography Forum.	Oct 2016
 Excellence Award, Crypto Contest Korea Cryptography Forum. 	Oct 2014
 Award for Excellence in Teaching Seoul National University. 	Aug 2014
■ Global PhD Fellowship (\$150,000) National Foundation Research of Korea.	Sep 2012–Aug 2017
■ BK 21+ Scholarship Ministry of Education of Korea.	Sep 2012–Aug 2017
 Best Award, Undergraduate Mathematical Olympiad 2006 Korean Mathematical Society. 	Nov 2006
 Excellence Award, Undergraduate Mathematical Olympiad 2005 Korean Mathematical Society. 	2005
 Silver Medal, the 45th International Mathematical Olympiad Athens, Greece. 	Jun 2004

INVITED TALKS

22nd Workshop on Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC 2018), Osaka, Japan.	
 Homomorphic Matrix Computation and Application to Neural Networks Microsoft Research, Redmond, USA. 	Jun 2018
 Approximate Homomorphic Encryption: Construction and Application The Second Homomorphic Encryption Standardization Workshop, Cambridge, USA. 	Mar 2018
 Homomorphic Encryption for Approximate Arithmetic Lattice and Cryptography Meeting, ENS de Lyon, France. 	Dec 2017
 Homomorphic Encryption for Arithmetic of Approximate Numbers 	Jun 2017

Nov 2018

Microsoft Research, Redmond, USA.

Post-Quantum Public-Key Encryption from LWR
Korea Internet and Security Agency, Korea.

Mar 2017

• Construction and Bootstrapping of Approximate Homomorphic Encryption

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS	 Multi Key Homomorphic Encryption from TFHE ASIACRYPT 2019, Kobe, Japan. 	Dec 2019
	 Multi Key Homomorphic Encryption with Packed Ciphertexts CCS 2019, London, UK. 	Nov 2019
	 A Full RNS Variant of Approximate Homomorphic Encryption SAC 2018, University of Calgary, Canada. 	Aug 2018
	 Bootstrapping for Approximate Homomorphic Encryption EUROCRYPT 2018, Tel Aviv, Israel. 	May 2018
	 Homomorphic Encryption for Arithmetic of Approximate Numbers ASIACRYPT 2017, Hong Kong. 	Dec 2017
	 Privacy-Preserving Logistic Regression based on the HEAAN Library iDASH Privacy & Security Workshop 2017, Florida, USA. 	Oct 2017
	 Secure Searching of Biomarkers Using Hybrid GSW Encryption Scheme iDASH Privacy & Security Workshop 2016, Chicago, USA. 	Nov 2016
	 Secure Sketch for Set Distance on Noisy Data 2014 KMS Annual Meeting, Yonsei University, Korea. 	Oct 2014
	■ A Group Action on \mathbb{Z}_p^{\times} and the Generalized DLP with Auxiliary Inputs SAC 2013, Simon Fraser University, Canada.	Aug 2013
OTHER ACTIVITIES	■ Co-chair of Mathcrypt'19	
	■ Program committees of PKC'20, iDASH'19, ICCD'19, iDASH'18	
OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE	 Visiting Scholar (Prof. Xiaoqian Jiang) Division of Biomedical Informatics, University of California, San Diego, USA. 	Jun 2017 – Sep 2017
	■ Intern (Prof. Damien Stehlé) Computer Science Department, ENS de Lyon, France.	Jul 2015 – Aug 2015
LANGUAGES	■ Korean: Native language.	
	■ English: Fluent.	
		[Last undate on 2010 11 21]

[Last update on 2019-11-21]